Congratulations on graduating!
In 1988 in my original life,
Kayo, Hiromi, and Nakanishi Aya went missing
and were later found dead.
I blamed myself for not being able to save anyone.
I tried my hardest to forget all about it...
and was left with nothing
but a gaping hole in my heart.
You've experienced joy, sorrow, success, and failure.
Today you graduate elementary school,
but you're all still lacking in many ways.
And I'm no different.
But I believe that filling the holes
in ourselves is what life's all about.
Hello.
Who're you?
I'm Fujinuma Satoru, a fifth-grader at Mikoto.
I'm Kobayashi Kenya.
I'm Sugita Hiromi.
Have we met before?
You're Nakanishi Aya-san, right?
I hear you're pretty good at piano.
I'm pretty good, yeah.
Have we met at piano class?
No, that's not it.
Say, what's that book you're reading?
Oh, this?
Shakespeare.
King Lear?!
I've only read Romeo and Juliet.
My parents keep pushing me to
play the piano and read Shakespeare.
What're they talking about?
Wanna get a little bit closer?
Ah! I thought you guys looked familiar!
You're the kids who're always sneaking
into that building across the river!
Our hideout is totally visible from here?
Hideout?
How childish.
Ch-Ch-Chi—
Don't call it childish.
You boys are always sneaking around,
making secret bases or hideouts or whatever.
I bet you pretend to be superheroes or something.
D-Don't make fun of superheroes!
Satoru-kun!
Anyway, I have to go.
Goodbye.
Hold it!
Kazu?
Huh?
Wh-What do you want?
Hideouts are...
a symbol of adventure for men!
Try visiting our hideout when you're free!
Then you'll understand!
You're a bunch of weirdos!
How childish.
Yesterday was fun, wasn't it?
So I really did forget those gloves
that I lost 18 years ago here.
I really don't like grinding.
But that's the fun part!
Hey, Satoru-kun,
Nakanishi-san should be at the park soon.
It's all good.
We can see her from here.
Ah.
We messed up pretty bad yesterday.
But how are we supposed to get closer to her?
I was free, so I figured I'd come see your hideout.
Welcome to our hideout!
Later!
Bye-bye!
Going to pick up Aya-chan again?
Yep. We'll both head to the hideout later.
Laters, then!
Laters, Sensei!
You mean "goodbye," young man.
I still can't believe those two got together.
I guess that solves the Nakanishi Aya problem.
Yeah...
Hey, Satoru-kun, Kenya-kun. Thank you both.
I think getting rid of loneliness is a great thing.
I know how it feels. I was always alone because
both my parents work and are never really home.
You helped me get rid of mine and asked me
to help to get rid of Kayo-chan's and Aya-chan's.
That made me really happy!
Hey!
Let's go to the hideout already! I'm sick of waiting.
Huh? Where's Kazu?
He went to pick up Aya-chan.
Why?
What do you mean, "why"?
I mean, she knows where the hideout is.
Well, yeah, but...
Whatever, let's go!
O-Okay!
Goodbye, Sensei!
Step on it!
Don't be in such a rush!
Wait for me!
That's right!
Nakanishi Aya.
Sugita Hiromi.
And Hinazuki Kayo.
The three of them were to be killed,
but they must no longer be targets at this point.
I'm not sure I can find him anymore, though,
now that I've lost all my leads.
There. Now you look even more like a girl.
Isn't it great?
Satoru.
Are we done playing detective?
Of course not. It's not over yet.
In 2006, my mother told Sawada-san that
she figured out who the real culprit was,
which means it was probably
someone she knew back in 1988.
Comparing it to Sensei's candy is weird,
but now that the killer has lost his targets,
he's surely looking for a substitute.
Move.
Well, we're gonna go watch the ice hockey game.
Is Hamada playing?
Of course.
Cool.
Tell him I wish him good luck.
'Kay.
Laters.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Have you noticed
Yanagihara-san's been all alone lately?
Misato?
She's become cut off from the rest of
the class after that whole lunch money incident.
I see.
I guess I'll try talking to her on Monday.
Okay.
Let's eat!
Oh, I might be a bit late today.
Okay, but call me as soon as you
know what time you'll be here.
Got it. Bye!
Have a nice day, Satoru!
Sensei said he'd give us a ride in his car!
Huh? Really?
Let's go and leave you-know-who behind.
Sounds good. Let's do it.
How can I start a conversation with her?
She's taking the bus?
Satoru.
I hear Misato's been all alone.
Yeah, but...
She's probably headed to Wakaba Gym.
Really?
Yashiro-sensei said he invited her
to go cheer on Hamada-kun.
Speaking of which, we saw her
watching the game by herself last week.
Thanks.
Want us to come?
Nah, it's probably better that I go alone.
I'm just going to see what's up, anyway.
Okay.
If we're still playing detective,
give us a report tomorrow.
Sure.
Come to the hideout if you need anything.
Okay. Laters!
Laters!
See you tomorrow!
Cya.
Laters!
He makes such a big deal out of it every day.
Tell me about it.
It's not like we won't see each other tomorrow.
Man, it's actually colder in here.
Go, Hamada!
Kick some butt, Kouichi!
Shut up, fugly! Just watch with your mouth shut!
Don't tell us what to do.
Watch your language, Kouichi.
Or else you won't get any food!
You've gotta be kidding me!
There she is.
And she really is all by herself.
All right, start warming up.
Okay!
At any rate, she'd make an ideal target
for a killer who's lost two others at once.
Oh, the toilet.
The game starts in five minutes!
Got it!
She's taking way too long.
I had to take a lollipop break.
What's the matter?
The game's about to start.
What are you doing here?
W-Well, uh, I wanted to talk to Misato.
Misato?
Huh?
Did she leave?
Yeah.
But the game hasn't even started yet.
The Shiratoris' truck?
Sensei, there's something
I have to check right away!
Help me!
If what you're saying is true, this is a crime here.
We call it "playing detective."
We pretend there's a kidnapper on the prowl
and talk to girls who are often alone
and make friends with them.
It's sort of a precautionary measure
against kidnappings.
Well, it doesn't matter if you're only
"playing" when you're getting results.
Thanks, Sensei.
Fasten your seat belt, Satoru.
Huh?
Oh, it's been acting up lately.
There we go.
So you've realized Misato has been all alone lately.
I actually didn't until Hiromi told me.
Still, I admire your spirit and bravery.
Really?
But this time, I hid behind the excuse
that things were awkward between us...
...and ended up using her like bait.
Bait, huh? You must be pretty serious about this.
So that's why you've suddenly been
awfully friendly with people lately.
Yeah. I want to fill the gaping
hole in everyone's hearts.
Both mine and other people's.
Crap! Those were Yashiro's words!
Great minds think alike, huh?
That's my exact philosophy in life.
I'd planned on talking about it on graduation
day if I was ever put in charge of sixth grade.
You may regret using Misato as bait, but there's
no need to feel guilty or ashamed about it.
Good deeds and bad deeds
are two sides of the same coin.
They're but things people do
to make up for their shortcomings.
That's an extreme way of thinking.
I've done all kinds of things to get
closer to a certain person myself.
Sometimes straightforward, sometimes roundabout.
I've even resorted to what you'd call "foul play."
It's been so much fun.
Er, a girlfriend?
I guess it is similar to romance in some ways.
At the very least, they're both ways
to fill a hole in one's heart.
Oh, want a candy?
Thanks, Satoru.
But there's no candy in there.
After all, this isn't my car.
What do you mean, this isn't your car?
Don't you think one's happiest moment
in life always changes?
Because mine changed just now.
Nothing beats that moment when
you fill that void in your heart.
When you find what you're looking
for and try to make it yours,
the more hurdles you face, the more happiness
you obtain when you overcome them.
I don't get it. What the hell is he talking about?
Laxatives?
I can tell you lied to me about one thing, Satoru.
You said you "pretend"
there's a kidnapper on the prowl,
but you're acting under
the certainty that there is one.
I refused to accept it. I couldn't believe it.
Or rather I didn't want to believe...
that someone could predict my thoughts.
Relax. Misato's not in that truck.
The only one in it is Shiratori Jun's father.
I had no idea until I saw you
following Nakanishi Aya that day.
The day I gave you and your mother a ride
was the day I was going to carry out my plan.
And yet, laughably,
there I was, seriously giving you
advice on how to steal my prey.
That was the second time you foiled my plans.
I began to suspect it was no mere coincidence.
So I urged the lonesome Misato
to watch the ice hockey games...
...and told Hiromi about it.
And if you showed up,
my suspicion would turn to conviction.
That you're my enemy.
No way...
I waited for the right time,
gave Misato a drink laced with laxative,
and ordered food parcels from Shiratori Foods.
It can't be...
It can't be!
All the pieces of the puzzle fell
right into place, just as I'd planned.
This is who I really am.
By the way, I picked up this car right before coming.
My standards for choosing a car
are a tad different from others.
There should be several cars of
the same make and color in the area,
so I can use them
as dummies whenever I want.
This is the first time they've ever come in handy, though.
I'm such a fool.
The truth was under my nose all along.
Kayo will be all right now.
I just didn't accept it.
Yashiro Gaku's name was on
the suspect list I saw at Sawada-san's place.
But because my mother's name was also on it,
I didn't think the list was important.
Because I trusted Yashiro so much,
I tried to remove him
from my own list of suspects.
But...
the killer is...
...the Yashiro I see in front of my eyes right now!
It's started to snow.
You can't take it off.
It's game over.
For the both of us.
I still can't believe it, Satoru.
You predicted my moves every step
of the way and destroyed my plans.
It sends shivers down my spine
that you've forced me into this.
It's almost like you've seen the future.
I don't want it keeping me up at night,
so let me get it out of the way.
What I'm about to do isn't an act of revenge
against you for foiling my plans.
I seriously do admire you.
Think of it as a substitute for
my desire that couldn't be fulfilled.
Didn't you say it was game over for you too?!
You're going to bring peace to this town, Satoru.
Isn't that exactly what you wanted?
And I'm going to bring upon your death
by my hands, and for my sake alone.
Screw you, Yashiro!
I won't die until I see you destroyed!
That's what they call being overambitious.
Yashiro, you bastard!
Screw you!
Damn it!
Da—
I've decided to leave this town.
Yashiro!
I know what lies in your future!
Crap...
It's freezing.
Shit!
Not good!
I'm going numb...
I'm screwed...
Oh, Ma.
What is it, Satoru?
Our eyes often met when I looked up at her.
Guys...
Satoru!
Satoru-kun!
Thank you, Satoru.
Kayo...
Airi...